# Raymond Muller | Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, United States | (925)-639-7520 | mullerr@purdue.edu

## Summary

Graduate Computer Science student with a computer vision, machine learning, and security background. I have interned at several government institutions working on various computer-related applications spanning computer vision, network security, software engineering, and web development. I am currently working on academic research on autonomous systems and perception under Dr. Z. Berkay Celik. I am also skilled in multiple different martial arts, have an open water diving certification, and I am a former Western States Chess Champion.

## Experience

**Graduate Research Assistant** – Purdue University

Aug 2022 — Present

Conducting research as part of the the PurSec Lab under Dr. Berkay Celik.

**Computational Engineering Student Intern** — Lawrence Livermore Ntnl Labs — Summers 2019 — Prsnt

Over the course of over 4 years I have worked on various aspects of Ground Penetrating Radar Systems, including implementing object detection systems, creating UIs through full stack development, and dockerization of certain applications.

**Doctoral Fellow** — National Security Innovation Network

June 2023 — Aug 2023

Worked on critical national security project sponsored by the Department of Defense.

**Graduate Teaching Assistant** — Purdue University

Aug 2020 — August

2022

Working with instructors and teams of 3-4 Teaching Assistants to lead instructional labs.

**Coach** — Apex Movement Norcal

Aug 2018 — Aug 2020

Main responsibilities included teaching parkour to lower level youth and adult classes, monitoring open gym, and providing assistance to the front desk.

**Student Intern** — CCC Department of Information Technology

Oct 2018 — May 2019

Worked on web and software development for Contra Costa County Tax Collector's Office.

**Teaching Assistant** — California State University East Bay

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

NSF-Technology Pathways TA under Dr. Jiaofei Zhong for Summer Quarter 2018. Work involved creating homework, slides, presentation materials, and assignments for students in the CS200 course using Python, with a Health-Sciences theme.

#### Education

Purdue University — PhD, Computer Science	2020 — 2024
Working in computer vision and security research under Dr. Berkay Celik.	
California State University - East Bay $-$ MS, Computer Science	2019 - 2020
Graduated with Master's of Science in Computer Science with a 3.97 GPA.	
California State University - East Bay — BS, Computer Science	2017 - 2018
Graduated Summa Cum Laude in December 2018	

#### **Publications**

- DRIVETRUTH: Automated Autonomous Driving Dataset Generation for Security Applications (Workshop on Automotive and Autonomous Vehicle Security, co-located at NDSS 2022)
- Physical Hijacking Attacks against Object Trackers (ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security 2022)
- That Person Moves Like A Car: Misclassification Attack Detection for Autonomous Systems
  Using Spatiotemporal Consistency (USENIX Security 2023)
- Evaluating perception attacks on prediction and planning of autonomous vehicles (USENIX Security 2022)
- Demo: Physically Hijacking Object Trackers (ISOC Symposium on Vehicle Security and Privacy, co-located at NDSS 2023)

## Talks / Lectures

- Guest Lecturer at Purdue, CS 592 IoT/CPS, "Machine Learning for Perception and Decision Making (April 4<sup>th</sup> 2022)
- Lightning Talk at Future Automotive Research Datasets: Challenges and Opportunities, invited by David Balenson at USC, "Automated Autonomous Driving Dataset Generation for Security Applications" (November 18<sup>th</sup> 2022)

### Certifications

- Certificate of Robotics Engineering and Programming with Vex (Villanova University)
- First Degree Black Belt in Tae Kwon Do (World Taekwondo Federation)
- Open Water Diving Certification (SDI)

## Skills

```
Computer Vision • Python • Computer Javascript • Robotics • Penetration Testing • Leadership • Web Development • Machine Learning • Research • C++
```

### Honors and Awards

- National Security Innovation Network X-Force Fellowship (June 5<sup>th</sup>, 2023)
- Purdue University Graduate Teaching Award (April 15<sup>th</sup>, 2023)
- ISOC Symposium on Vehicle Security and Privacy Best Demo Award Runner Up (February 27, 2023)
- ISOC Symposium on Vehicle Security and Privacy Travel Grant Awardee (2023)
- General Motors Security AutoDriving Security Award (April 24, 2022)
- Western States Chess Champion.
- Junior Olympic Swimmer